Guide to the Foster Hall Collection, 1800-1952 CAM.FHC.2011.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Foster Family, 1800-1952; II.
  - Foster Family Manuscripts, 1800-1900; 3.
    - Correspondence, 1800-1950
      - From Dunning Foster to Morrison Foster, December 13, 1854; C545
        Distraught to hear that ma is sick; willing to help however he can; Dunning is still ill; needs to borrow money from him; Henry owes him money and should make an effort to pay Morrison to make up Dunning's share of the family expenses; travel plans.
      - From Dunning Foster to Morrison Foster, December 21, 1854; C546
        William will loan him $300, asking Morrison to send William the note for what Morrison owes Dunning as collateral; note about interest in note; note by Morrison that he sent Dunning the note 12/27/54.
      - From Wilson McCandless to Mr. J. Stewart, January 20, 1855; C547
        Cannot be pallbearer for Eliza's funeral because of urgent matters; asking Stewart to find someone else.
      - From Dunning Foster to Morrison Foster, October 10, 1855; C549
        Acceptance of $200, where it can be sent, his travel plans.
      - From Dunning Foster to Morrison Foster, October 18, 1855; C550
        Check has arrived, thank you for your kindness.
      - From Dunning Foster to Morrison Foster, march 17, 1856; C551
        Very weak because of the weather; please send your acceptance for $200; not so sick that you need to come, shouldn't have stayed here this winter; note by Morrison that Dunning died soon after the letter w/ Henry, Morrison, & Stephen in attendance.
      - From Ann Eliza Buchanan to Morrison Foster, April 8, 1856; C552
        Grief at hearing of Dunning's death; waiting to hear the details of his funeral; News of William, Jr., whose wife Elizabeth is about to die, hopes grief brings the remaining children closer together.
      - From William B. Foster, Jr., to Morrison Foster, April 23, 1856; C554
        Enclosed his share for Dunning's funeral; still has hope Elizabeth may recover; family news.
      - From James Buchanan to Morrison Foster, December 26, 1856; C555
        Cannot yet send the money he owes him; visiting William's; family news.
      - From L.L. Lighthouse to G.P. Garner, April 15, 1857; C556
        Can find no record of Dunning having land in that county.
      - From William B. Foster, Jr., to Morrison Foster, December 5, 1857; C557
        He is lonely & would like Morrison to spend the winter with him; advising Morrison of appointment as Collector of Pittsburgh.
      - From Edward Buchanan to Morrison Foster, February 15, 1858; C558
        Thanking him & William for the 3 tickets to the address; advising him who will be using them.
      - From Lidie Wick to Morrison Foster, February 23, 1858; C559
        Family and social news.
      - From Lidie Wick to Morrison Foster, May 27, 1858; C560
        Has switched to larger paper since he prefers it; have you heard from Uncle Steve, I wonder if he is moved yet?; social & family news.
      - From Henry B. Foster to Morrison Foster, July 5, 1858; C561
        Social news.
      - From Harriet Buchanan to Morrison Foster, August 22, 1858; C562
        Inviting him to Sunday school festival.
      - From Mary Wick to Morrison Foster, November 3, 1858; C563
        Social news; updated him on lawsuit; when might she go to St. Louis?
      - From Mary Wick to Morrison Foster, November 6, 1868; C564
        Thanking him; will go to Pittsburgh first; "before starting for St. Louis."
      - From Lidie Wick to Morrison Foster, April 10, 1859; C565
        Betsy Skinner has invited them to visit, Liddie is very anxious to hear Morrison's opinion.
      - From Mary Wick to Morrison Foster, May 30, 1859; C566
        Wants to visit Cousin Hannah in St. Louis very badly, mother won't promise if she can go, she won't spend a dime all spring to save money; social news.
      - From Henrietta Thornton to Morrison Foster, June 10, 1859; C567
        Remembered it's his birthday, contacted Thomas Struthers about "the matter we spoke of"; pray for Morrison & Stephy, the only two to remain willfully out of the church; I beg you to find God; family news.
      - From Lidie Wick to Morrison Foster, June 15, 1859; C568
        Describing visit to Cousin Eliza's; family news.
      - From Lottie Foster to Morrison Foster, July 23, 1859; C569
        Describing trip to Bedford Springs, wish he was there.
      - From James Buchanan to Morrison Foster, August 9, 1859; C570
        Enclosing repayment of loan, did not include interest, but is willing to loan money to Morrison should he ever need it.
      - From Lottie Foster to Morrison Foster, August 18, 1859; C571
        Family & social news.
      - From William Foster, Jr., to Morrison Foster, September 10, 1859; C572
        Note enclosed with note for $1500 for endorsement.
      - From Carrie Skinner to Morrison Foster, September 19, 1859; C573
        News of her family since he departed.
      - From Lottie Foster to Morrison Foster, August 30, 1859; C574
        General family news.
      - From Lottie Foster to Morrison Foster, February 6, 1860; C575
      - From William Foster to Morrison Foster, July 14, 1860; C576
        Thanking him for articles he sent him; general family news; added note that he died 3 weeks after writing the letter.
      - From Edward Buchanan, Jr., to Morrison Foster, March 31, 1860; C577
        Surprised to hear of Morrison's marriage; news of life at West Point.
      - From Mary Crosman to Morrison Foster, June 16, 1861; C581
        Explaining her stance on the house situation, general news.
      - From Lottie Foster to Morrison Foster, August 29, 1860; C582
        Family news.
      - From L.J. Cist to Morrison Foster, 1865; C583
      - From L.J. Cist to Morrison Foster, March 1, 1865; C584
        Thanking him for the photos he loaned him, asking for another item of Stephen's.
      - From Edward Buchanan to Morrison Foster, November 30, 1874; C586
        Enclosing the $300 for the note Morrison holds against James.
      - From Ann Eliza Buchanan to Morrison Foster, February 11, 1874; C587
        Someone requested a complete list of Stephen's songs to bind for the library, she needs to Morrison to make the list; family news.
      - From Ann Eliza Buchanan to Morrison Foster, March 1, 1875; C588
        Congratulating Jessie on her confirmation; thanking them for their condolences; Willie's last days; general family news.
      - From Ann Eliza Buchanan to Morrison Foster, April 29, 1876; C589
        Railroad in place, hoping he will visit soon; Alice is engaged.
      - From Ann Eliza Buchanan to Morrison Foster, August 31, 1876; C590
        Explaining when the best time for him to visit will be, family news.
      - From Ann Eliza Buchanan to Morrison Foster, March 15, 1877; C591
        Acknowledging the "Stephen Foster Serenaders" program he sent; family news.
      - From William Foster, Sr., to William Foster, Jr., February 20, 1837; C592
        Business.
      - From William Foster, Sr., to William Foster, Jr., June 17, 1832; C593
        Business; politics, canal; family news.
      - From William Foster to Eliza Foster, January 20, 1826; C594
        Mr. Wilson; his activities while away from home; enclosing a letter for William.
      - From Ann Eliza Foster to William Foster, March 23, 1828; C595
        God talk, news of the family.
      - From Eliza Foster to William Foster, Jr., September 16, 1841; C596
        Her confidence in her husband has been restored; family news.
      - From William B. Foster to William Foster, Jr., October 1, 1941; C597
        His claim; temperance; his portrait; election.
      - From William B. Foster to William Foster, Jr., October 11, 1841; C598
        His claim/lawsuit; Henry's future; job prospects.
      - From Eliza Foster to William Foster, Jr., October 18, 1841; C599
        Stray cat; Stephen is not so much devoted to music as he was; family & social news; pray for William.
      - From Dunning Foster to William Foster, Jr., October 23, 1841; C600
        Receipt for William, Sr's portrait by Cogswell; business and election news; description of portrait.
      - From Eliza Foster to William Foster, Jr., November 10, 1841; C601
        Christ Church; ask him to hold onto Etty's note; description of her typical day.
      - From William Foster to William Foster, Jr., November 22, 1841; C602
        Job offer from Walter Howard; his claim/suit; needs to borrow $50; Stephen seems inclined to join you..and go to school at Athens.
      - From William Foster to William Foster, Jr., 1841; C603
        Instructions for when Henry comes; wants to borrow William's car if he brings it to fetch Eliza.
      - From Henry Foster to William Foster, Jr., December 20, 1841; C604
        Description of accommodations and stay in Washington City; description of his job; description of Washington statue.
      - From William Foster to William Foster, Jr., July 29, 1829; C605
        Enclosing check for William to buy salt; Stephen and Jim have whooping cough.
      - From Lavinia Day to Eliza Foster, June 23, 1822; C606
        Misses her, tales of her life.
      - From Lavinia Day to Charlotte Foster, November 16, 1823; C607
        Praising her and her family; tales of her life.
      - From Eliza Foster to William Foster, Jr., May 28, 1836; C608
        From Philadelphia; visit to the mint; regards to the family.
      - From Henry Foster to Eliza Foster, March 10, 18?6; C609
        Telling of his travels.
      - From William B. Foster to William Foster, Jr., August 7, 1832; C610
        Congress, his work, canal.
      - From Eliza C. Foster to William Foster, Jr., March 24, 1841; C611
        Has come to peace with the wrongs she suffered in the past; there are accommodations if he comes to visit; "poor little Stephen how is he I think of him very much of late."
      - From William B. Foster to William Foster, Jr., September 14, 1833; C612
        Enclosing a note for $200 with instructions; found a source for $300; business news.
      - From William B. Foster to Charlotte Foster, September 12, 1825; C613
        Sending package via stage; Ann Eliza has enclosed note.
      - From William B. Foster to Charlotte Foster, June 22, 1829; C614
        To Louisville; advising her to remain in Louisville b/c the river is too low; family news.
      - From Ann Eliza Foster to William Foster, June 16, 1832; C615
        The "boys are just recovered from the sore throat", general news, request that he retrieve books for her.
      - From William B. Foster to William Foster, Jr., February 8, 1833; C616
        From Harrisburg; recovered from jaundice; joined the temperance society; confessional news.
      - From Ann Eliza Buchanan to Eliza Foster, May 7, 1833; C617
        From Meadville; description of her activities; arrived safely.
      - From William B. Foster to William Foster, Jr., June 2, 1833; C618
        Enclosed letter from Mr. McAnulty for William's information; reminding him to send blank note with his name signed to it.
      - From William B. Foster to William Foster, Jr., June 1, 1833; C619
        Has not gotten the $100 due from Mr. McAnulty, needs William to send him $100; Ma with Henrietta and Stephen left two weeks ago for Augusta, Kentucky, where Eliza has brothers; family news; asking him to send endorsed blank note; got a raise.
      - From William B. Foster to William Foster, Jr., July 4, 1833; C620
        Letter with $100 note received; Ma, Stephen, & Henrietta have returned; two cholera deaths in town.
      - From William B. Foster to William Foster, Jr., October 5, 1833; C621
        Information about local election.
      - From Henrietta Foster to William Foster, Jr., September 27, 1833; C622
        Eliza had a toothache; Stephen had his eye bitten by a spider; family news.
      - From William B. Foster to William Foster, Jr., December 15, 1833; C623
        Thanking him for $150 note; business; would like to see him when he goes to Harrisburg; family news.
      - From William B. Foster to William Foster, Jr., February 24, 1834; C624
        Arrived in Harrisburg; Dunning McNair promised him money; money matters; family news.
      - From William B. Foster to William Foster, Jr., March 14, 1834; C625
        Returned from Harrisburg; submitted his resignation; money matters; needs his signature to renew note; needs his advice on what to do; family news.
      - From William B. Foster to William Foster, Jr., May 18, 1834; C626
        Living in new house; Ann Eliza had a baby; William should writer to KY congressman about his matter; politics; family news.
      - From William B. Foster to William Foster, Jr., June 12, 1834; C627
        Information about election, "The boys are all at home going to school."
      - From William B. Foster to William Foster, Jr., July 14, 1834; C628
        Anxious about not having heard from him, info on Ann Eliza and Buchanan, justification as to why he quit his job, "Little Stephen is learning fast."
      - From William B. Foster to William Foster, Jr., August 3, 1834; C629
        Anxious about not having heard from him, family plans.
      - From William B. Foster to William Foster, Jr., September 24, 1834; C630
        Family news; enclosing newspaper.
      - From William B. Foster to William Foster, Jr., December 7, 1834; C631
        Buchanan's improved health, financial plans, family news.
      - From William Foster, Sr., to William Foster, Jr., January 5, 1835; C632
        Family news, boys can go ice skating.
      - From William Foster, Sr., to William Foster, Jr., March 16, 1835; C633
        Sold coal lot, boys are at school.
      - From Henrietta Foster to William Foster, Jr., March 21, 1835; C634
        Social news; family news.
      - From Henrietta Foster and Mary Wick to William Foster, Jr., June 9, 1836; C636
        Social and family news.
      - From Henrietta Foster to William Foster, Jr., October 16, 1835; C636A
      - From William Foster, Sr., to William Foster, Jr., October 30, 1835; C637
        Enclosing letter from Scott, explaining his viewpoint, and his take on the money scandal.
      - From William B. Foster to Eliza Foster, March 2, 1836; C638
        Failed to get money from the government; his travel plans, family news.
      - From William B. Foster to William Foster, Jr., April 10, 1833; C639
        Enclosing note for $250; needs him to send a note for $200; money matters; Ann Eliza's wedding; family news.
      - From William B. Foster to William Foster, Jr., May 8, 1837; C641
        Business news; family news.
      - From William B. Foster, Jr., to Eliza Foster, May 14, 1837; C642
        His travels and activities; future plans.
      - From Henry Foster to Eliza Foster, May 31, 1837; C643
        Arrived in Columbus; descriptions of his activities, social news.
      - From Ann Eliza Buchanan to Eliza Foster, June 5, 1837; C644
        News of her family; misses and loves her parents and prays for them.
      - From William B. Foster to William Foster, Jr., June 6, 1837; C645
        Status of the publication of William, Jr.'s, dissolution with Hall; family news; financial news.
      - From William B. Foster to William Foster, Jr., June 8, 1837; C646
        Money is being held for him until his instructions are received; Hard ware store has gone under.
      - From Eliza Foster to William Foster, Jr., June 16, 1837; C647
        Family news; Stephen has recovered from the whooping cough and going to school with Morrison to Mr. Todd; church news; social news; Pa has made a garden.
      - From William Foster, Jr. to William Foster, Sr., July 2, 1837; C648
        Includes a copy of an agreement between William B. Foster, Jr., and Samuel McKelvy. Response to dissolution with Hall being published; business plans; copy of agreement between William, Jr. & McKelvy.
      - From William B. Foster to William Foster, Jr., July 16, 1837; C649
        Little Stephen went with Eliza to Uncle Struthers; he needn't worry about the Hall matter; political and financial state of the country.
      - From William B. Foster to William Foster, Jr., September 5, 1837; C650
        Clayton's balloon trip; business matters; family news; Eliza thanks him for the $20 he sent her.
      - From William B. Foster to William Foster, Jr., August 14, 1837; C651
        Business matters; Henrietta's baby; family news; social news.
      - From Henrietta Foster Wick to William Foster, Jr., September 4, 1837; C652
        Family news; Mary is ill and it would be good if he would come home; social news.
      - From William B. Foster, Jr., to William B. Foster, September 29, 1837; C653
        From outside of Bardstown; business matters; travel plans; was ill but is now well; needs him to make a suit for him for an "extraordinary occasion" upon his return.
      - From William B. Foster to William Foster, Jr., October 11, 1837; C654
        Mr. Fisk's death and the claim against him; description of suit being made for William, Jr.; family and social news.
      - From William B. Foster to William Foster, Jr., October 29, 1837; C655
        Mary was ill but is better; news of his claim against Wilkins.
      - From Lidie Wick to William Foster, Jr., January 9, 1838; C656
        News of Mary's death, description of her last moments & funeral.
      - From Henry Foster to William Foster, Jr., March 12, 1838; C657
        Cost of tombstone and description of it; family and social news.
      - From William B. Foster to William Foster, Jr., March 19, 1838; C658
        Court meets today; Buchanan family visit; wants to know if he can raise the money.
      - From Henry Foster to William Foster, Jr., April 21, 1838; C659
        Thanking him for $50 note; Pa was able to arrange for a place for William on the Canal Commission in Allegheny; portraits arrived; Pa's claim; description of local legal case.
      - From William B. Foster to William Foster, Jr., April 16, 1838; C660
        News of McNair and his decision; needs written permission from William, Jr., to enter decision into docket; family news.
      - From William B. Foster and Henry Foster to William Foster, Jr., May 13, 1838; C661
        Family and social news; not sure if power of attorney is sufficient; Henry's new business arrangement.
      - From William B. Foster and Henry Foster to William B. Foster, Jr., June 12, 1838; C662
        Family and social news; Henry is disappointed that he hasn't heard from him.
      - From William B. Foster to William Foster, Jr., June 20, 1838; C663
        News of Henry's business and his partner; George Baldwin; need money.
      - From William B. Foster, Jr., to William B. Foster, July 9, 1838; C664
        News of his business activities; his travel plans.
      - From William B. Foster to William Foster, Jr., July 16, 1838; C665
        Repeating info from his last letter in case it wasn't received; trying not to borrow money from store; wants William to not pay the next bill that comes due; family news; election news; social news.
      - From William B. Foster to William Foster, Jr., August 1, 1838; C666
        Business news; Eliza is better.
      - From William B. Foster to William Foster, Jr., August 18, 1838; C667
        Asked William to draw on his note at a different bank to save face and make it appear it was a loan; closed up business with Skinner; election news; explanation of the Judge Wilkins' note.
      - From William B. Foster to William Foster, Jr., October 20, 1838; C668
        Election news; Thomas Wick is about to open a store; Ann Eliza's new baby; social news; he's going to apply for his old job; business news.
      - From Henrietta and Thomas Wick to William Foster, Jr., October 21, 1838; C669
        Family news; glad to hear he may be visiting.
      - From William B. Foster to William Foster, Jr., October 24, 1838; C670
        Business news; Mr. Stevens' note; needs permission to pay Stevens' note; politics.
      - From William B. Foster, Jr., to Eliza Foster, November 27, 1838; C671
        Business activities; social news; trying to make arrangements to come to Penna for winter; description of venison meal.
      - From William B. Foster to William Foster, Jr., December 5, 1835; C672
        Business news.
      - From William Foster, Jr., to William B. Foster, December 28, 1838; C673
        Enclosing permission to transfer judgment; will not make it home in January as hoped; needs Pa's help submitting job application for the canal commission; politics; business news.
      - From William B. Foster to the Canal Commission, February 11, 1839; C674
        Letter of application for William, Jr., for the Canal Commission.
      - From William B. Foster to William Foster, Jr., March 25, 1839; C675
        Informing him of appointment as principal engineer.
      - From Henry Foster and William B. Foster to William Foster, Jr., April 15, 1839; C676
        Dictating the letter for Pa; upset that they haven't heard from him; job is being held for him until they hear of his acceptance or refusal; copy of Thomas Struthers's letter; wants him to partner with John Homery in the lumber business.
      - From William B. Foster, Jr., to William Foster, April 22, 1839; C677
      - From William B. Foster to William Foster, Jr., April 30, 1839; C678
        Business news, discussion of William's appointment.
      - From John Struthers to William B. Foster, Jr., July 1, 1839; C679
        Needs to borrow $100 to get accommodations renovated for the Foster's; canal.
      - From William Foster, Jr., to William B. Foster, March 30, 1839; C680
        His appointment; his schedule; business.
      - From William Foster to William B. Foster, Jr., July 26, 1839; C681
        Henry told Pa of William's desire to rent a farm, drawings and description of the properties.
      - From William B. Foster to William Foster, Jr., July 26, 1839; C682
        Descriptions of more farms, description of current lodgings; Morrison & Stephen board at Mr. Reno's going to a free school; family news.
      - From Henrietta and Thomas Wick to William Foster, Jr., September 29, 1839; C683
        Family and social news; postscript by Thomas Wick; Stephen enjoys himself finely.
      - From William B. Foster to William Foster, Jr., October 23, 1839; C684
        News clipping enclosed; business matters; land he intends to buy as Sheriff's sale in William's name; needs to borrow money; family news; mention of "disease" that has afflicted him.
      - From William B. Foster to Morrison Foster, January 12, 1840; C685
        Family news; we have concluded to let Stephen go with William who will put him to school at the academy in Towanda…I think it's an excellent chance for the dear little fellow to get an education; concerned about Morrison's health; telling him to study.
      - From Eliza C. Foster to Morrison Foster, January 21, 1840; C686
        Wants to know if William gave him money; encouraging him to behave and study.
      - From William B. Foster to William Foster, Jr., January 27, 1840; C687
        Business news; surely Stephen must feel grateful to you for your brotherly kindness to him at Pittsburgh, and will I trust exert him by carefully pursuing your advice and instruction; family news.
      - From Eliza C. Foster to Morrison Foster, February 7, 1840; C688
        Family news; feel quite contented about Stephen; believe that William will take good care of him; he took him to see the Governor, the house of reps, and a fine concert in Harrisburg; encouraging him to work hard.
      - From William B. Foster to William Foster, Jr., March 24, 1840; C689